# PERSONAL PROFILE

An ambitious full-stack developer with a passion for developing and designing for the web and beyond. Over 5 years commercial experience in a web developer role, and vast experience with web technologies outside of the workplace. Able to learn new technologies quickly and effectively to suit any kind of project. Strong desire to build upon my existing knowledge and further myself as well as contributing to a team of like-minded people.

# **KEY SKILLS**

**Main technical skills:** Linux server admin (AWS/Gcloud/DigitalOcean), React, Typescript/Javascript, PHP, Node.js, CSS/SCSS/Tailwind, SQL, Jquery, Three.js, Git/CI

Other skills: Figma, Photoshop

## **EXPERIENCE**

**Pomegranate Media** Sept 2021 to present Lead Web Developer

- Overall management of a wide range of client websites, applications and services. ECommerce, financial and brand related.
- Managing continuous integration and delivery of websites on a variety of stacks, from LAMP & LEMP to JAMstack applications.
- Building and maintaining complex load balanced web architecture's, using AWS, GCloud and DigitalOcean.
- Managing a team of other developers, harnessing devOps, git flow and CI processes to optimise delivery of work.

# Melt Design Dec 2019 to Sept 2021

Web Developer

- Development of in-house set of Wordpress plugins/themes to cater for all sorts of internal and client requirements
- UNIX/Linux server management and diagnostics
- Managing deployments/updates for complex projects using devops systems
- Managing and training a small team of web developers

#### **E3D-Online** Sept 2017 to Dec 2019

Web Developer

- Responsive front end development using HTML, CSS & JavaScript
- Magento2 and Wordpress PHP development (custom themes, plugins etc.)
- Managing LAMP/LEMP server configurations and code deployments using automation tools like Ansible

## **EDUCATION**

**Lancaster University - Computer Science and Mathematics** 

October 2013 to July 2016 1st Class degree

**Sawtry Community College - A-Levels** 

September 2011 - July 2013 Maths (A), Business(A), IT(B), Physics(C - at AS level)

## **INTERESTS**

Travel: I have a love for visiting new places and experiencing different cultures. I spent a year in New Zealand working and travelling.

Football: Play for local team. I captained my university college team which involves organising everything like squads and training. Avid Manchester United fan.

Web development: I follow many Front End web development accounts on twitter and keep up with latest trends and new libraries etc.

3D printing - I own a 3D printer and also enjoy using CAD software to make my own custom parts for various projects

## **EXTRAS**

See portfolio of some of my web development work ~ ryans1224.qithub.io